## **Pablo Garcia**

Software Engineer

pgrfpgm@gmail.com

367-382-6269

Edmonton, Canada

Iinkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-815bb31b9

pablogr.dev

Experienced software engineer with a diverse skill set spanning data engineering, SQL, and web development. I specialize in designing and optimizing high volume of data in applications. My passion lies in seamlessly integrating data solutions with web development, offering efficient solutions. You can go to my personal website to know more about me.

#### Work Experience

CDS, a Hewlett Packard Enterprise company, León (Spain) Subsidiary of Hewlett Packard Enterprise with over 1500+ employees and \$300M+ annual revenue.

# **Business Applications Engineer** 06/2021 to 07/2023

- Created ETLS with Python using Requests, SQL Alchemy, Pandas, etc.
- Automated data collection with python using multithreading and data optimizations.
- Manage a SQL Server database creating highly optimized tables, views, stored procedures, and triggers.
- Configured and deployed the applications in a Red Hat Enterprise Linux server.
- Conducted quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Promoted to Business Applications Engineer II after a year working in the company.

### Internship

03/2021 to 05/2021

- Create applications using Power Apps and Power Automate
- Create dashboards to display information using Power BI
- Created an application using microservices architecture with Spring (java) and Kafka.

#### Key projects I made in my free time.

**Guess the draw** (3 months using MEAN stack)

• Browser-based game in which one player draws a provided word while the remaining players attempt to guess the drawn object or concept using socket.io to synchronize both the chat and the drawings in each of the rooms.

#### Skills

## Programming languages

- Python
- SQL (SQL Server)
- NoSQL (MongoDB)
- Typescript
- Java
- HTML5
- CSS

#### Frameworks and Libraries

- Django, Django-Rest
- NodeJS
- Angular2
- Angular Material
- Express
- Spring boot
- Bootstrap
- Socket.io
- Docker (Docker compose)

### **Development Software**

Git

#### Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (fluent)

#### Education

CIFP Ponferrada

Web application development 2019 – 2021, Ponferrada (Spain)

### Other

 PCAP Certified Associate in Python Programming